

Mir Sakhawat Hossain

Mathematician and Techie



2 January 1991



Dhaka, Bangladesh



+88 01726801630



mirsakhawathossain.github.io



s.hossain18@gmail.com

About me —

I am a dedicated, proactive and hard working person with a strong background in Mathematics. I have experience in planning and carrying out experiments, researching scientific literature and writing technical reports. I also have a good experience in Mathematical Analysis, Data Science, Machine Learning, E-Marketing and online reputation management. I possess excellent analytical and communications skills and a dedicated approach to working in a highly controlled working environment. I am eager to learn and enjoy overcoming challenges. My greatest passion in life is using my technical know-how to benefit other people and organizations.

Skills -

Linux & Cloud Computing

MS Office & Data Science

Python & Git Version Control

PHP & Javascript

HTML & CSS

Fortran

Career Objective

To become a dynamic and versatile person who is capable of merging innovative ideas and facing challenges and also establish myself in and organizational environment where honesty, creativity, punctuality, sincerity and performance are the key to success.

Education

2014-2015 M.Sc. Kabi Nazrul Government College

Majoring in Mathematics

CGPA: 2.64

2009-2010 B.Sc. Honours National University

Majoring in Mathematics

CGPA: 3.01

2006-2007 HSC Dhaka Board

Science Group. GPA: 4.50

Institution: Dhaka Imperial College

2004-2005 SSC Dhaka Board

Science Group. GPA: 4.88

Institution: Dhaka Collegiate School

2012-2013 Professional Course on Web Design I-Mesh Multimedia

Grade: A

2020 COVID-19 Data Analysis Using Python Coursera Guided Project

Achievement: 100%

Language Proficiency

Bangla Mother Tongue English Second Language

Publications

2018 SALSA is an ICT based educational tool for Astrophysics students

to study structure and dynamics of Milky Way Galaxy Hossain, Mir Sakhawat, and Banrupa Mallik. "SALSA is an ICT Based Educational Tool for Astrophysics Students to Study Struc-

ture and Dynamics of Milky Way Galaxy." In 2018 21st International Conference of Computer and Information Technology (IC-

CIT), pp. 1-6. IEEE, 2018.

Experience

2012-2013 E-Marketing Professional Workshop Trainer JobsBD

Trained Data Driven Professional Digital Marketing to Freelancers

2014-2016 E-Marketing Professional and Consultant Upwork Provided Data Driven Digital Marketing Services and Consultancy

2016-2017 Social Media Data Analysis Github

Social Media Data Mining and analysis for predictable activities

using Python

2020-Pres. Machine Learning Application for Asteroid Dataset Github

Asteroid Data Mining and predictive analysis for Asteroid Classification and size prediction using Machine Learning and Deep Learn-

ing in the field of Astronomy

2020-Pres. Machine Learning Application for Exoplanet Dataset Githut

Exoplanet Data Mining and predictive analysis for Exoplanet Detection using NASA Exoplanet Transit Database, Machine Learning

and Deep Learning in the field of Astronomy



Mir Sakhawat Hossain

Mathematician and Techie



2 January 1991



Dhaka, Bangladesh



+88 01726801630



mirsakhawathossain.github.io



s.hossain18@gmail.com

About me —

I am a dedicated, proactive and hard working person with a strong background in Mathematics. I have experience in planning and carrying out experiments, researching scientific literature and writing technical reports. I also have a good experience in Mathematical Analysis, Data Science, Machine Learning, E-Marketing and online reputation management. I possess excellent analytical and communications skills and a dedicated approach to working in a highly controlled working environment. I am eager to learn and enjoy overcoming challenges. My greatest passion in life is using my technical know-how to benefit other people and organizations.

Skills -

Linux & Cloud Computing

MS Office & Data Science

Python & Git Version Control

PHP & Javascript

HTML & CSS

Fortran

Personal Profile

Details

Name: Mir Sakhawat Hossain Father's Name: Mir Sayed Hossain Mother's Name: Fowzia Ahmed

Present Address: 4 No Madan Shaha Lane, Sutrapur, Dhaka- 1100

Permanent Address: Vill- Hoglakandi, P.O.- Chala, P.S.- Harirampur, Dist-Manikganj

Date of Birth: 2 January 1991

Sex: Male Blood Group: B +ve

Height: 5 Feet 11 Inches
Marital Status: Unmarried
Religion: Islam

Nationality: Bangladeshi(By Birth)

Reference

Referee

Prof. Md. Mohsin Mia
Department of Mathematics
Kabi Nazrul Govt. College
Cell No- +8801711-022712

Prof. Dr. Farseem Mannan Mohammedy
Department of Electrical Electronic Engineering
Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology(BUET)
Cell No- +8801715-044474
Email- farseemm@gmail.com

Declaration

I hereby certify that, to the best of my knowledge and belief, this CV correctly describes my-self, my qualification and experiences.

MITC Sookhawat Hossoin

(Mir Sakhawat Hossain) Date: December 19, 2020